reliant.com 2019-04-24

# Privacy Statement | Reliant

We know that you care how information about you is collected, used and shared, and we appreciate your trust that we will do so carefully and sensibly. This Privacy Statement applies to the use of all products, services, websites, and mobile applications offered by Reliant and offered by Reliant and our affiliates, unless they have a different Privacy Policy. This Privacy Statement outlines the information Reliant will collect and how we will use that information. 

#### What Information We Collect

Reliant's primary goal in collecting information is to allow us to offer products and services which are relevant to consumers like you. Personal information also allows us to provide services and features that most likely meet your needs, and to customize our service to make your experience smooth and efficient. Any personal information that we collect will only be used for internal marketing purposes of Reliant, except as otherwise required by law or as disclosed to you in this Privacy Statement. The information we collect:

  * **Information You Give Us**   
Reliant will not collect any personal information from you unless you provide it to us voluntarily. We may ask you to provide information including your name, address, government-issued identification card number, social security number, telephone number, and email address. In addition, we may ask you to provide information relating to energy use, such as the characteristics of your home, your age, gender and family size, or we may ask you to state your opinion about potential products and services. If you opt not to provide us with personal information, we may be unable to deliver certain promotions or product information to you that you have requested.
  * **Non-personal, Aggregate and Statistical Data**   
Reliant may collect certain non-personal or aggregate data. For example, we may use web log information (such as your web browser, operating system, pages visited, etc.) and use cookies when you visit many of our web pages. For instance, when you visit one of our websites, our web server will automatically recognize some non-personal information, including but not limited to the date and time you visited our site, the pages you visited, the referrer (the website you came from), the type of browser you are using (e.g. Internet Explorer or Safari), the type of operating system you are using (e.g. Windows or Mac), and the domain name and address of your Internet service provider (e.g. AT&T or Comcast).
  * **Email Addresses**   
At the time Reliant requests an email address from you, you will be given the opportunity to indicate whether or not you wish to receive future email solicitations from us. We may, however, send you emails for other reasons such as responding to your requests for service or information or matters relative to your account.
  * **Information from Other Sources**   
For reasons such as improving our products and services, making product recommendations or special offers that we think will interest you and to identify persons not already a Reliant customer, we receive information from other sources and add it to our information. The type of information we receive may include (but is not limited to) your name, address, telephone number, and in some cases, type and characteristics of your home, your age, and statistical estimates of your family size, income and home value. We also sometimes receive updated delivery and address information so that we can correct our records and deliver your next communication more easily.

Back to Top

#### How We Collect Information

  * **Information You Give Us**   
Reliant does not require potential customers or visitors to our websites to provide personal information, except as necessary to be enrolled as a customer. You may choose to enter contests, vote in polls or otherwise express an opinion, subscribe to one of our services such as newsletters, or participate in one of our online forums or communities. These programs may require you to submit some information in order to participate. These programs and the types of information required are described in more detail below.
  * **Registration/Subscriptions**   
To fully use our websites, visitors may need to register using our online registration forms, where visitors may be required to provide us with some personal information. Visitors may also be asked to select a user ID and password. Further, to register for certain services or become a member of certain communities, we may ask visitors to submit their name, email address, home address, and zip code. You can further make choices about receiving targeted newsletters and alerts from Reliant. You can always decide not to receive or stop receiving any targeted solicitations from Reliant that you do not want.
  * **Contests/Sweepstakes**   
Reliant may run contests, sweepstakes and other promotions. We may ask you to provide personal information that is needed in order to administer the contest, sweepstakes or promotion and to notify winners.
  * **Referrals**   
Occasionally, you will have the opportunity to forward promotional opportunities or other information on the website to friends/relatives or to send messages from our web sites to friends/relatives. This personal referral information you provide to facilitate this communication is used on a one-time basis and is not further retained by Reliant, except in circumstances where we obtain consent from the people you have referred to receive communications from us.
  * **Questionnaires, Surveys and Profile Data**   
Reliant may occasionally ask you to complete surveys and opinion polls about your interests, needs, and attitudes. Surveys help us provide better services and products that meet customer needs. Participation is voluntary and these surveys are optional.
  * **Customer Services and Contact Information**   
If you provide our customer service representatives with feedback on your experiences with our products/services or otherwise submit questions to our customer service representatives or webmasters, you will be asked to supply personal information for our record keeping and follow-up.
  * **Non-personal, Aggregate and Statistical Data**   
Reliant may collect certain aggregate data called web log information and use cookies when you visit many of our web pages. For instance, when you visit one of our websites, our web server will automatically recognize some non-personal information, including but not limited to the date and time you visited our site, the pages you visited, the referrer (the website you came from), the type of browser you are using (e.g. Internet Explorer or Safari), the type of operating system you are using (e.g. Windows or Mac), and the domain name and address of your Internet service provider (e.g. AT&T or Comcast).
  * **Information from Other Sources**   
For reasons such as providing better product recommendations or special offers that we think will interest you and to identify persons not already a Reliant customer, we receive information from other sources and add it to our information.

Back to Top

#### How We Use Your Information

  * **Personal Information**   
We may use your personal information to contact you. For example, we may send you marketing or promotional materials including emails or other information; we may respond to your comments or requests for information; or we may contact you if needed in the course of fulfilling your service request. We may also use your personal information to confirm and verify your customer enrollment status, and for credit approval. Reliant does not collect personal information automatically, but we may combine non-personal information collected automatically (e.g., through cookies and web beacons) with your previously submitted personal information. We may also enhance or merge personal information with data obtained from third parties for the same purposes. We use this personal and statistical information about you to improve our marketing and promotional efforts; to statistically analyze site usage; to improve our content and product offerings; and to customize our sites' content, layout and services. We may also use your information to deliver information to you that, in some cases, is targeted to your interests, such as targeted banners, new services and promotions. We believe these uses allow us to improve our site and better tailor it to meet our visitors' needs. Reliant occasionally sends emails describing new products, promotions or events. These email services are optional and you may opt-out of these services completely, at any time.
  * **Non-personal, Aggregate and Statistical Data**   
Reliant uses web log information (such as your web browser, operating system, pages visited, etc.) to help us design our website, to identify popular features, and for other managerial purposes. However, web logs may be used if necessary to help identify any person attempting to break into or damage our website. We may share web log information with law enforcement agencies if we believe that we have evidence of a violation of computer security or related laws.

Back to Top

#### How We May Share Your Information

  * **For Promotional Purposes**   
Except in the event of a business transfer, we will not share, trade or sell personal information about you for promotional use by any business, other than Reliant and its affiliates. Subject, to any applicable legal restrictions, we may share personal information about you with our affiliates and any vendor we use to support our business or provide service to you, including any rewards partner. If you provide your consent for non-affiliates to market their products and services to you, we may share personal information about you for that purpose. We may sometimes send offers to Reliant customers on behalf of other businesses. When we do this, we do not give that business the name, address, telephone number or email address of our customers. We may share information with third parties and business partners that is in aggregated or anonymous form so that it does not divulge personal information, and may work with those entities to do research, including for marketing purposes, and to provide and improve products and services. When companies acquire other businesses, sell all, or portions of their business, customer information generally is one of the transferred assets. If Reliant or substantially all of its assets are transferred through merger, acquisition, bankruptcy or any other change of corporate control then, customer information will of course be one of the transferred assets. Aggregated and statistical data from our website visitors may be shared with our partners. For example, we may let a partner know that approximately "20,000 people visited a web page regarding a specific joint promotion." All employees, contractors and other companies engaged by Reliant for work that involves access to personal information are contractually required to keep the information confidential and not to use it in any way other than what is necessary to perform their work for Reliant.
  * **For Protection of Reliant and Others**   
We may release personal data, including account information, when we believe release is appropriate to comply with laws, regulations or judicial orders; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Reliant, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. Reliant also reserves the right to share the information to respond to duly authorized information requests of governmental authorities or where required by law or regulation.

Back to Top

#### Accessing Your Personal Information

If you want to know what personal information Reliant holds about you, or you wish to change personal information that is inaccurate or out of date, please contact us at [privacy@reliant.com](mailto:privacy@reliant.com "Privacy"). Please note that it may not always be possible to modify or completely remove information in our databases, although we will make reasonable efforts to do so upon your written request.

Back to Top

#### Disposal of Your Personal Information

Reliant maintains your personal information in our records when you are a customer. We also maintain personal information for a period of time after you are no longer a customer if necessary for the purposes for which it was collected. These purposes may include business, legal or tax purposes. If these purposes no longer apply, we will destroy, or de-identify, or anonymize the information in accordance with our internal policies and applicable law.

Back to Top

#### Cookies and Web Beacons

When you view one of our websites, we may collect some non-personal information about you. The collection of this non-personal information is done either through the "cookie" technology or with "web beacons" (also called "single-pixel gif" or "web pings"). Neither our cookies nor web beacons nor web log information collects any personal information. They do not contain personal information such as your name or email address.

  * **Cookies**   
When you view one of our websites or interactive advertisements, we may store some information on your computer. This information will be in the form of a small text file, also called a "cookie". Cookies help us in many ways to make your visit to our website more enjoyable and meaningful to you. For example, cookies avoid you having to log in every time you come back to one of our websites. They also allow us to tailor a website or advertisement to better match your interests and preferences. Most browsers can be configured not to accept cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent.
  * **Web Beacons**   
Web beacons are site instrumentation that help us to determine, for instance, whether a page has been viewed or not and, if so, how many times. When you ask us to send you information on a promotion or a newsletter, we may use web beacons to establish how many of the emails are actually opened. In general, any electronic image viewed as part of a web page or email, including an ad banner, can act as a web beacon. Third party advertising networks that serve ads onto any Reliant website may use cookies and/or web beacons in their advertisements. Reliant retains no control over such third party cookies and/or web beacons and does not have access to the information related to third party cookies and/or web beacons.

Back to Top

#### Children's Privacy

Reliant believes that it is especially important to protect children's privacy online. The Reliant websites are not directed at children and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children.

Back to Top

#### Data Security

Reliant is committed to keeping the data you provide us secure and will take reasonable precautions to protect your personal information from loss, misuse or alteration, including limiting access to such information within Reliant to authorized individuals and destroying personal information that we decide not to retain in a manner designed to make it unreadable or undecipherable. Agents, contractors, or partners of Reliant who have access to your personal information in connection with providing services for Reliant are required to keep the information confidential and are not permitted to use this information for any other purpose than to carry out the services they are performing for Reliant.

Back to Top

#### Your Preferences

Reliant allows you to choose to receive or stop receiving solicitations from us. We accomplish this by maintaining a “Solicitation Preference File” in which we record your preferences to receive or not receive solicitations from us. We use two suppression files provided by the Direct Marketing Association, the Mail Preference Service and Telephone Preference Service files; and we use the National Do Not Call Registry. In addition, we use the Statewide do-not-call and Electric do-not-call lists maintained by the Public Utility Commission of Texas. The Statewide do-not-call list is used to identify those consumers that do not wish to be contacted by telephone regarding any solicitation. The Electric do-not-call list is used to identify consumers or businesses that do not wish to be contacted by telephone regarding their choice of electric provider.

#### How to Make Your Preferences Known

**To Reliant**

You may inform us of your preference not to receive solicitations from us in one of two ways. Submit your preferences online with the requested information.

Write us at:

Reliant

Solicitation Preferences

P.O. Box 3765

Houston, TX 77253-3765

When contacting us by mail, be sure to include your name, address, telephone number, and email address. In addition, please indicate your preferences for postal mail, telephone and email communications from Reliant.

**To Other Businesses**

If you wish to reduce the amount of national advertising mail or telephone solicitations you receive at home, you may register with the Direct Marketing Association Mail Preference Service and Telephone Preference Service for free by writing to the following addresses:

DMA Mail Preference Service

P.O. Box 643

Carmel, NY 10512

DMA Telephone Preference Service

P.O. Box 1559

Carmel, NY 10512

Be sure to include your complete name, address and telephone number and sign the request.The Mail Preference Service and Telephone Preference Service are consumer services provided by the Direct Marketing Association. When you register for these services, direct marketers will use the information you provide to purge your name, address and telephone number from their marketing campaigns. You should see a reduction in the amount of national advertising solicitations you receive within ninety days of registering with the service. Before making your final decision about registering with the Direct Marketing Association or if you wish to learn more about the privacy initiatives of the Direct Marketing Association, consider visiting the following web site: [www.dmachoice.org](http://www.dmachoice.org/ "dmaChoice"). You may also register online for MPS and TPS at the above web site. There is a fee to register online.

**To the Public Utility Commission of Texas**

The PUC has established two do-not-call lists. You can indicate to the PUC that you do not wish to receive telephone solicitations from providers of electric service regarding your choice of service provider by placing your name, address, and telephone number on the electric do-not-call list. You can indicate that you prefer not to receive any telephone solicitations by placing your name, address, and telephone number on the statewide do-not-call list. The PUC charges a fee for this service. For more information or to register your name, address, and telephone number on the do-not-call lists you may use one of three different methods.

Online - [texasnocall.com](http://texasnocall.com/ "Texas No Call List")

By phone – call toll-free 512-936-7120   

By mail – request an application from

Texas No Call

P.O. Box 313

East Walpole, MA 02032

**To the National Do Not Call Registry**

The National Do Not Call Registry gives you a choice about whether to receive telemarketing calls at home. For more information, go to [donotcall.gov](https://donotcall.gov/ "Do Not Call").

Back to Top

#### Complaints

Reliant is committed to working with consumers to obtain a fair and rapid resolution of any complaints or disputes about privacy. Please send us your questions or comments regarding our privacy practices either by sending an email to [privacy@reliant.com](mailto:privacy@reliant.com "Privacy") or by writing a letter to:

Reliant Privacy Compliance Coordinator

P.O. Box 3765

Houston, TX 77253-3765

We will be happy to respond to your questions and comments.

Back to Top

#### Links to Other Sites

Some Reliant websites and mobile applications may contain links to other sites. Reliant is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites. We recommend you carefully read the privacy policies of each site you visit.

Back to Top

#### Policy Changes

We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Statement from time to time. If at some time in the future, we wish to use your information for new unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our Privacy Statement, we will:

  * Post the policy changes to this section of our Privacy Statement to notify you of these changes and provide you with the ability to opt out of these new uses.
  * Initially, we will only use information collected from the time of the policy change forward for the new purposes. However, after a reasonable time has transpired, we will use for the new purpose the information collected before the policy change from those who do not opt out.

Back to Top

#### Your Acceptance of Our Privacy Practices

By using this website, our mobile application or any other Reliant website or interactive banner ads, you signify your acceptance of this Privacy Statement, and you adhere to the terms and conditions posted on the website. If you do not agree with any of these terms, please do not use this site or submit any personal information. This English version shall always prevail in case of conflicts between it and any translations of our Privacy Statement.

Back to Top

#### For Your Convenience

Please print the Reliant Privacy Statement (this page) for your records.

Back to Top

_Revised: January 11, 2018_   
_REL11118_
